Chris Lyons



administrator@suncoast.systems



linkedin.com/in/dotcomrow



2025706514



https://resume.suncoast.systems

Summary

Strategic business systems developer for the U.S. Postal Service (USPS), with a 15-year record of creating some of the most transformative and profitable software systems in the organization's history. Spearheaded the design of USPS Click-N-Ship and poboxes.usps.com. Led development teams that, combined, enabled the generation of more than \$1B in annual revenue and spearheaded the USPS's effort to reassert its place as one of the most trusted international shipping services in the U.S.

Left USPS to join Accenture, a leader in cloud transformation and a top development organization assisting companies, large and small, in preparing and executing cloud migration strategies, assisting organizations with cloud native development approaches, and embedding those focuses into an organizations development approach from top to bottom.

In my spare time I have been working on developing my own private cloud system based on Openstack (currently using the Wallaby release) for both learning the ins and outs and details of infrastructure and development tools used for cloud native development.

Experience



Application Development Senior Analyst

Accenture

Aug 2019 - Present (3 years 10 months)

Designed and developed solutions for AIQ, Convoy, and other internal and external applications at Comcast along with started new internal initiatives based on code quality, security, and release management.



Sr. Analyst / Systems Engineer

United States Postal Service

Jun 2004 - Aug 2019 (15 years 3 months)

Progressed through increasingly responsible roles to develop, enhance and maintain high performance systems, applications and tools vital to core business operations and all USPS.com website functions. Analyze and translate complex requirements into functional specifications. Lead and support all phases of project and SDLC.

- * Credited with driving on-time delivery of numerous multimillion-dollar projects, effectively negotiating through technical challenges, changing requirements, and often disparate priorities of stakeholder communities.
- * Recognized as Subject Matter Expert for design processes and key resource for high risk projects, and application performance issues.
- * One of a select group entrusted by senior executives in 2011 to turn around massive \$200 million project to completely redesign USPS.com website. Finished project in 6 months after 2+ years of delays.
- * Played integral role in redesigning and enhancing functionality of 'Click-N-Ship', the largest revenuegenerating application on USPS.com. Completed project in half the time. Responsible Architect for

redesigning Click-N-Ship application (ins.usps.com) from an Apache-Struts framework based app to a micro services design.

- * Took lead role in design and development of new enterprise AddressBook containing 65 million records.
- * Instrumental in design and deployment of Electronic Customer Care (eCC) Pilot application, an enterprise solution for web self-service and case management.
- * Designed and deployed ePayroll application.
- * Architect responsible for redesigning Poboxes Online site (poboxes.usps.com) from an Apache-Struts framework based application to a micro services architecture.

Programmer Analyst

United States Postal Service

Jun 2004 - Aug 2009 (5 years 3 months)

Contributed to high profile Webvars project; part of team assigned to complete initial documentation for Integrated System Methodology process.

Assistant Manager

Blockbuster

Jan 1998 - Jan 2003 (5 years 1 month)

Promoted through ranks from initial position as Cashier, managing up to 3 staff members while overseeing daily store operations. Simultaneously pursued and obtained B.S. in Computer Science.

Education



Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 1998 - 2002

Licenses & Certifications

> OWASP Overview - Accenture 24652985

A10 and A9: API and Component Attacks - Accenture 24653545

> Top 10 List Items - Accenture 24653023

> A8 and A3: Cross-Site Attacks - Accenture 24653138

> A7 and A6: Leaky and Unprepared Applications - Accenture 24653248

> A4 and A2: Broken Applications - Accenture 24653402

> A5 and A1: Security and Injection - Accenture 24653424

> A10 and A9: API and Component Attacks - Accenture 24653545

Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP) 2019: Core Concepts -Accenture 24653583

Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP) 2019: Secure Coding Practices - Accenture 24653621

- Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP) 2019: Threat Modeling
 Accenture
 24749821
- > Secure Design Accenture 24750007
- CCSP 2019: Application Development & Security Accenture 24750085
- CISSP: Risk Management Accenture 24750272
- Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP) 2019: Secure Design Principles - Accenture 24750303
- Data Security and Access Control Accenture 24952094

Skills

Java • JavaScript • Java Enterprise Edition • Core Java • PL/SQL • Concourse CI • GoCD • Agile Methodologies • Python (Programming Language)